<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Zach Marino</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/pages/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Zach Marino</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zmarino.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/pages/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/pages/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/pages/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/pages/about/</guid>
        <description>
&lt;a href=&#34;Resume-Zach-Marino.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    View Resume
&lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;I am a digital-focused UX designer with a background in Computer Science and Experience Design, meaning I can go beyond the mockup and breathe life into projects with my technical understanding. I hope to pursue a meaningful career in UX design and UX engineering. My goal is to bridge the gap between code and design, developing prototypes and frameworks that are already compatible with current and future technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer, I am working at Dow Jones as a Product Design Intern, and this fall I will be continuing my education at Northeastern University, pursuing a Master&amp;rsquo;s in Experience Design. Previously, I worked as a Product Manager at the Boston Globe, where I used my knowledge of computer science and design to prototype and implement a major project on the 2024 roadmap. I graduated Magna Cum Laude from Northeastern University with a Bachelor’s in Computer Science and Design in Spring 2025 — a year early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of my work, I enjoy listening to music, street photography, baseball (go Guardians!), and catching a show on Broadway!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
