<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Featured Work on Zach Marino</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/categories/featured-work/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Featured Work on Zach Marino</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zmarino.com/categories/featured-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>TalentTrace</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/TalentTrace.png" alt="Featured image of post TalentTrace" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;TalentTrace is a job tracker and aggregate job data app that my group and I created for our final project in CS3200 Database Design. Users can add jobs entries to TalentTrace and see all of their applications at a glance. They can also see aggregate data from all job entries to see and analyze market trends. Recruiters can use TalentTrace to keep track of applicants and any interviews they have with them. The project repository can be found on my github or by clicking the button below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zachmarino234/TalentTrace&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Repository
&lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tech-stack&#34;&gt;Tech Stack
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our tech stack consists of MySQL for the database, Flask for the backend, and Streamlit for the frontend. This stack was provided to us in a template created by our professor that we forked. Each tier was containerized using docker. While DevOps was not the focus of this project, since finishing this project I have investigated and learned how to setup a similar tech stack and containerize every tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;database&#34;&gt;Database
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our database is coded in MySQL and contains a DDL file as well as several files housing mock data generated by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.mockaroo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mockaroo&lt;/a&gt;. Before coding the database files, we first did a very basic design iteration and identified our users and their needs. We then took those needs and translated them into a large Entity-Relationship diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/ER-diagram.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;9120&#34;
	height=&#34;3168&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/ER-diagram_hu10766316028567349892.webp 480w, https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/ER-diagram_hu17367962809626122217.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Entity-Relationship Diagram (Click on image for better quality)&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;287&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;690px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the diagram ready to go, we translated it into a DDL file which was set to run every time the MySQL docker container was spun up using &lt;code&gt;docker compose up db&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;backend-api&#34;&gt;Backend API
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We built our API using Flask. Our professor provided the template for the project so all setup was done for us, we just needed to create routes and blueprints to connect the database to the frontend. We created a blueprint for each entity that required a route like job entries, users, etc. We also had a route for all of our aggregate queries. An alternative method to connect the database to the frontend would have been to create a couple of large routes and running any specific queries in the frontend using pandas but that would have bad practice. It is better to keep the database and frontend as separate as possible, and it was easier to just create extra routes or abstract already made routes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/backend.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1262&#34;
	height=&#34;670&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/backend_hu9941428779200126990.png 480w, https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/backend_hu13926516439020606257.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Example of a GET route for the aggregate data page&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;188&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;452px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frontend&#34;&gt;Frontend
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our frontend was built with Streamlit, a data visualization tool written in python. Streamlit was not built to run an application like our project, but the focus of the class was not on front-end development and Streamlit was easy to pick up as everything is prebuilt. We mocked user authentication using buttons and session states and created flows for each persona. Each persona needed to have a GET, PUT, POST, and DELETE route. Our project was not graded on UX or visual design, but considering my skillset, I wanted to add some design elements to make sure our app felt good to use despite the limited framework. We added confirmation messages to any forms, downloaded more advanced data viz frameworks to better display the data, and I created a logo to add an extra touch of cohesiveness to our project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/frontend.png&#34;
	width=&#34;3024&#34;
	height=&#34;1594&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/frontend_hu14423125621602959699.png 480w, https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/frontend_hu14148629253610771638.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aggregate job data page from the system administrator persona&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;189&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;455px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;logo&#34;&gt;Logo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zmarino.com/posts/talenttrace/logo.svg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TalentTrace logo designed by me&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time with the logo as it did not impact our grade but I still wanted to make something interesting (or at least better than the AI generated logos other teams were using). The &amp;ldquo;trace&amp;rdquo; in TalentTrace reminded me of a light/spotlight which is represented by the yellow streak that runs through the two T&amp;rsquo;s. The blue was chosen because it complemented well with the yellow when I was picking colors. The geometric look was used because we felt it looked professional without being generic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to this class, my last computer science class was Algorithms which really killed a lot of my interest in computer science. This project brought my enthusiasm back. It was incredibly fun learning how to bring all of these different parts of software engineering together into a cohesive product. I feel like I finally see the full picture in regards to what I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning and it also made me realize I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; design or computer science, I want to do both. I still find backend development (specifically algorithms) intimidating but I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to enjoy databases as much as I did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chain - A Word Connecting Card Game</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/Chain%20logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Chain - A Word Connecting Card Game" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chain is a card game I designed in a group in Design Perspectives (ARTG1001) taught by Northeastern Professor Lee Moreau during the Fall 2023 semester. There were no rules on what our game had to be or how it was played, it just had to be accessible to most skill levels. My job in the group was to develop the rules for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took on the ruleset because prior to this project, a majority of my design work had been for a digital medium so I wanted to explore a physical medium and challenge myself with a new type of design. My groupmates worked on the visual design of the cards and the instructions, and we all contributed to the list of words we would put on the cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;Game-process-portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alloc8 - Personal Finance Project</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/Alloc8%20logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Alloc8 - Personal Finance Project" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alloc8 is a personal finance app that I created in ARTG 2400 Interaction Design Principles, taught by Professor Sofie Hodara, for my final project. We started in small groups and did user research together, interviewing our friends and family about their personal finance habits. From these user interviews we developed an idea of what users wanted from a personal finance app, and created our own seperate prodicts to solve this design issue. I ended up on a personal finance app that automatically allocates your paycheck into rent, budgets, spending goals, etc. as decided by the user, and the extra money left over can be used to either temporarily increase budgets or add to other goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;Alloc8-Process-Portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>MOHAI Native Stories</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/MOHAI.png" alt="Featured image of post MOHAI Native Stories" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the first half of Summer 2023, I did a program at Northeastern’s Seattle campus, where I took a user experience design class (CS4973 is the generic special topics class code). Throughout that class, we were tasked with a design project relating to the Museum of History and Industry (MOHAI) in the South Lake Union area (by the Amazon Headquarters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In groups, our job was to propose a redesign of a certain part of the Indigenous Peoples Exhibit. My group focused on the Native American stories they had playing throughout the exhibit on screens. Our job was to reimagine how people interacted with these stories.
We completed a full cycle of the design process using common brainstorming tools like Miro and prototyping tools like Balsmiq Wireframes and Axure RP. While Figma is the primary design tool I use, this project was a good way to learn other software and expand my skill set as a designer. It was also the first time I worked on a design project with a real client as compared to a made-up scenario for a class project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;MOHAI-Process-Portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
