<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Boston Globe on Zach Marino</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/boston-globe/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Boston Globe on Zach Marino</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 17:16:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/boston-globe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Boston Globe Co-op Retrospective</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/boston-globe-retrospective/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/boston-globe-retrospective/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Late 2023, I accepted a co-op position as a product manager at the Boston Globe starting in January of 2024. I completed the six month co-op term then stayed on part time for another two months until August 2024. I worked primarily on the Boston.com team but also worked on other Globe projects like the corporate website. I also participated in innovation week, which is an initiative where all employees are invited to brainstorm and build a pitch to address pain points or flesh out creative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned&#34;&gt;What I learned
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary hard skills I learned were related to product management and design. I learned how to coordinate work on a project, ticket and prioritize issues, and take in stakeholder feedback to align our goals with the wider editorial mission of the Boston Globe. I also learned how to collate and analyze key performance indicators, , and work within the Wordpress ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of soft skills, I learned how to function and get work done in a corporate environment, stay on top of meetings, converse with stakeholders and coworkers, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite parts about working at the Globe was that since my team was so small, I was able to jump around and do different tasks that weren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily part of my job description. A great example of this is a project I was working on towards the end of my co-op term. While I can&amp;rsquo;t share any specifics as it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been released yet, it was a project that required developers to style in a niche format with complicated documentation. I took on the challenge of doing it myself and managed to code it all for the developers. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do this as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hired as a web developer, but I wanted to because I felt that to get the most out of my co-op I should challenge myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This challenge I gave myself (along with the Database Design class I was taking concurrently while being part-time) helped me realize that what I wanted to do post-college wasn&amp;rsquo;t strictly computer science or design, but rather the combination of both in the form of UX engineering. I sincerely thank all my coworkers and my boss, Richard Rinker for giving me the opportunity to learn, grow, and contribute to the Boston Globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I also found out I was good at company softball ;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Boston Globe Innovation Week 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/innovation-week/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/innovation-week/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/posts/innovation-week/Hack-Day-2022.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Boston Globe Innovation Week 2024" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every quarter, the Boston Globe hosts an event called &lt;strong&gt;innovation week&lt;/strong&gt;, which is an initiative where all employees are invited to brainstorm and build a pitch to address pain points or flesh out creative ideas. The best ideas are looked into and potentially implemented depending on the scope of the work and its alignment with company values. The judges consisted of company executives and the Boston Globe innovation team, as well as voting from other participants. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bostonglobemedia.com/innovation/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More information on the innovation week initiative can be found on the Boston Globe corporate website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the only co-op of 32 to pitch an idea, and the executive staff responded to my proposal favorably. The Globe even transferred my idea to the innovation team to be investigated further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-proposal&#34;&gt;My Proposal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(This description of my proposal is intentionally left vague as my entry to innovation week is intellectual property of the Boston Globe)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my first couple of months at the globe, I noticed the way we display the scores of Boston sports games was really basic and lacked any particularly good user experience. Specifically, the banner that shows up on the homepage of Boston.com did not fit with the style of the rest of the website and only showed the score. I figured that the banner could use a facelift and we could use the opportunity to make the banner much more detailed and user-friendly. Boston sports are an especially big part of the culture and my project sought to capitalize on that love for Boston sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;product-research&#34;&gt;Product Research
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With my proposal in mind, I looked into our competitors for sports content and how we differed from them. I also learned that according to the Data Sports Group, an estimated 80% of sports fans used a second screen when watching a sports game. I found out that our competitors either didn&amp;rsquo;t focus on Boston sports coverage exclusively (like CNN for example) or their level of detail only appealed to enthusiasts (like ESPN for example). Globe properties fit into the middle ground of these two extremes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface-design&#34;&gt;Interface Design
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before starting my first iteration, I first determined what metrics and features I wanted to include in the banner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
