<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>UI/UX on Zach Marino</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/tags/ui/ux/</link>
        <description>Recent content in UI/UX on Zach Marino</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 17:16:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zmarino.com/tags/ui/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>[IN PROGRESS] CAMD Honors Project</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/honors-project/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/honors-project/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/honors-project/honors-project.svg" alt="Featured image of post [IN PROGRESS] CAMD Honors Project" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Investigating the Impacts of Design Thinking on the Journalistic Process&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Supervising Professor:&lt;/strong&gt; Sofie Hodara&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project seeks to answer what it means to think like a designer through the exploration and designed intervention of the domain of journalism and the journalistic process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who recently started her co-op as a living/arts reporter for the Boston Globe. When I was talking to her about work, she mentioned she was stuck thinking of pitches to show her editor. My advice to her was to think like a designer: Who am I writing for? What are the demographics and interests of my audience? What stakeholders are involved? These are natural thoughts to have when creating a product (or in this case an article) but the conscious act of considering these factors allows us to narrow down our audience. With these questions answered, she adjusted her pitches and got two accepted, gaining a byline in her first week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can think like a designer, but what separates a designer from other jobs that also problem-solve? What does it mean to “think like a designer?” I plan to answer this question by investigating a specific domain and designing a solution. In the spirit of my friend and my 8 months as a Product co-op at the Boston Globe, I want to redesign the journalistic process for reporters. Specifically, I want to synthesize different elements of popular design kits (like the one created by IDEO) and alter them to apply specifically to arts/culture/lifestyle/sports reporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deliverables&#34;&gt;Deliverables
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UX research, including personas, user stories, sketches, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low, medium, and high-fidelity prototypes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Usability Scale Results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final presentation of research, product, and results\&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project will be broken up into five phases:\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 1: Audit different design kits and their characteristics - 1 week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 2: Audit the journalistic process and create a wireframe of a potential solution - 2 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 3: Test process on existing toolkits - 1 week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 4: Create a new design kit to fit in with the journalistic process - 1 month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 5: Test the new kit with journalists (System Usability Scale) - 2 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 6: Analysis of Results - 1 week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My supervising professor and I will meet once a week for 30 minutes to check in and discuss progress on each phase. The primary constraint with these phases are tracking down reporters, interviewing them, and having them test out a solution. I have a couple of leads I can follow to get people involved, including my former co-workers at the Globe and the BU/The New School journalism schools. I plan to meet with these contacts individually and talk to at least 3 of them for each phase requiring user input. I plan to do a weekly exercise to reflect on the thought processes practiced in other professions besides reporting, reflecting on my findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chain - A Word Connecting Card Game</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/chain/Chain%20logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Chain - A Word Connecting Card Game" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chain is a card game I designed in a group in Design Perspectives (ARTG1001) taught by Northeastern Professor Lee Moreau during the Fall 2023 semester. There were no rules on what our game had to be or how it was played, it just had to be accessible to most skill levels. My job in the group was to develop the rules for the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took on the ruleset because prior to this project, a majority of my design work had been for a digital medium so I wanted to explore a physical medium and challenge myself with a new type of design. My groupmates worked on the visual design of the cards and the instructions, and we all contributed to the list of words we would put on the cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;Game-process-portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alloc8 - Personal Finance Project</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/alloc8/Alloc8%20logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Alloc8 - Personal Finance Project" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alloc8 is a personal finance app that I created in ARTG 2400 Interaction Design Principles, taught by Professor Sofie Hodara, for my final project. We started in small groups and did user research together, interviewing our friends and family about their personal finance habits. From these user interviews we developed an idea of what users wanted from a personal finance app, and created our own seperate prodicts to solve this design issue. I ended up on a personal finance app that automatically allocates your paycheck into rent, budgets, spending goals, etc. as decided by the user, and the extra money left over can be used to either temporarily increase budgets or add to other goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;Alloc8-Process-Portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Ethics of Dark Patterns</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/ethics-of-dark-patterns/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/ethics-of-dark-patterns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ethics of Dark Patterns is a paper and final project I wrote for my Tech Regulations of Digital Platforms class (CS4973) taught by Northeastern Law professor Elettra Bieti. The paper discusses the conception and proliferation of dark patterns, and how they can potentially be regulated from both a legal and ethical standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark patterns are defined as instances where designers use their knowledge of human behavior (e.g., psychology) and the desires of end users to implement deceptive functionality that is not in the user’s best interest &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3174108&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;(Gray et al., 2018, p.1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To read the paper, click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;The-Ethics-of-Dark-Patterns-Zach-Marino.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Paper
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>MOHAI Native Stories</title>
        <link>https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:16:35 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://zmarino.com/posts/mohai-native-stories/MOHAI.png" alt="Featured image of post MOHAI Native Stories" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the first half of Summer 2023, I did a program at Northeastern’s Seattle campus, where I took a user experience design class (CS4973 is the generic special topics class code). Throughout that class, we were tasked with a design project relating to the Museum of History and Industry (MOHAI) in the South Lake Union area (by the Amazon Headquarters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In groups, our job was to propose a redesign of a certain part of the Indigenous Peoples Exhibit. My group focused on the Native American stories they had playing throughout the exhibit on screens. Our job was to reimagine how people interacted with these stories.
We completed a full cycle of the design process using common brainstorming tools like Miro and prototyping tools like Balsmiq Wireframes and Axure RP. While Figma is the primary design tool I use, this project was a good way to learn other software and expand my skill set as a designer. It was also the first time I worked on a design project with a real client as compared to a made-up scenario for a class project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To see the detailed design doc click the button below.&lt;/strong&gt; ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;MOHAI-Process-Portfolio.pdf&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Design Doc
&lt;/a&gt;
  
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
